Guide to the Meyer Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Meyer family papers
1917-1934
MS 763
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
Correspondence, photographs, clippings and memorabilia of the Meyer family of Ada, Ohio documenting family activities during World War I. The five brothers, all Yale graduates, served overseas.
Meyer family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Harriet Smith in 1976.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
William Walter Meyer (1887-1969): general counsel of the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad. Karl Frederick Meyer (1891-1971): real estate agent; officer with the Detroit Trust Company. George Arthur Meyer (1894-1971): chairman, Modern Languages Department of Utah State University; author of several books. Charles Grafton Meyer (1896-): lawyer; vice President and director of Citizens Saving Bank, Stamford, Conn.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, photographs, clippings and memorabilia of the Meyer family of Ada, Ohio documenting family activities during World War I. The five brothers, all Yale graduates, served overseas.
Families; World War, 1914-1918; Ada (Ohio); Soldiers; Meyer, Charles Grafton, 1896-; Meyer, George; Meyer, Karl Frederick, 1891-1971; Meyer, Russell Jay, 1892-1918; Meyer, William Walter, 1887-1969; Smith, Helen Meyer, 1889-1976; Myers family; Yale University -- History
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - William Walter Meyer (1887-1969), 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Helen Meyer Smith, (Mrs. Earl R.) (1889-1979), 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Karl Frederick Meyer, (nickname "Abe") (1891-1971), 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Russell Jay Meyer, (nickname "Y") (1892-1918), 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - George Arthur Meyer, (nicknames "Sock," "Tike," and "Tyke") (1894-1971), 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Charles Grafton Meyer, (nickname "Boy") (1896-), 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Meyer family, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Condolences for Russell J. Meyer, including 1 TLS W. G. Harding, 1918 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous orders, programs, printed material, 8 post cards, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper clippings World War 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memorabilia, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Liberty War scrapbook, Circa 1916-1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Diploma, commissions, and certificates, 1896, 1916-1918, undated (Box 2)